[ Crowd Sounds ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Welcome everyone and thank
&gt;&gt; 欢迎大家
you for coming to this session.
感谢你们参加本次会议
My name is Athar Shah.
我叫 Athar Shah
And I'm a manager here at Apple
是 Apple Core Media 软件团队的
in the core media software team.
一名经理
And we at Apple are really
今天 Apple
excited to talk to you today
很高兴与你们
about two new media
谈谈两项
technologies.
全新的媒体技术
In particular, we're going to be
具体而言 我们将讨论一个全新的
talking about a new codec for
针对视频和图像压缩的
video and image compression
编解码器 叫做 HEVC
called HEVC and a file format
和一个我们即将采用的
for images that we're adopting
图像文件格式
called HEIF.
叫做 HEIF
But before we get into the
但在我们了解
details, if you've downloaded
更多细节之前
the developer seed, the latest
如果你已经下载了开发者预览版
build, then on certain iOS
的最新构建版本
devices you are already
那么在一些特定的 iOS 设备上
capturing and using these new
你已经获得并使用了
technologies and file formats.
这些新的技术和文件格式
And if you pay close attention,
如果你足够细心
you'll notice that these files
你就会发现
are a lot smaller than they used
这些文件比之前
to be.
小了很多
Later on in the presentation,
在接下来的介绍中
Gavin will talk to you about the
Gavin 会与你们讨论
specifics of our platforms and
我们平台的一些细节
how we support these
以及我们是如何
technologies in hardware and in
在硬件和软件中
software.
支持这些技术的
So we're going to be going over
我们首先会讨论
the landscape of media as it is
目前媒体技术的概况
today, why we need to change.
和我们需要改变的原因
We'll talk about what are HEVC
然后我们会讨论
and HEIF and why we decided to
HEVC 和 HEIF 分别是什么
adopt them here at Apple.
以及为什么 Apple 决定采用它们
And then finally, we'll give an
最后，我们会简单介绍一下
overview of how we've adopted
我们是如何在 Apple 生态系统中
these technologies within the
应用这些技术的
Apple ecosystem and then also
并且指导你
provide some guidance on how you
如何在你的 App 中
can take advantage of these
针对你的使用情况
within your apps for your use
充分利用
cases.
这些技术
So let's talk about media today.
我们首先来谈谈目前媒体的格局
The world is becoming more and
我们的世界正在变得
more visual.
越来越可视化
And both consumers and producers
顾客和制作商
are generating more and more
都在生成越来越多的视频
video and media related content.
和多媒体内容
Not only that, the content is
不仅如此 现在的多媒体内容
taking new forms like high
正在以各种全新的形式呈现
resolution 4K video, HDR video,
如高分辨率 4K 视频  HDR 视频
wide color or wide gamut video
或广色域视频
and so on.
等等
The nature of media is also
媒体的性质也
changing with, you know, our
正在改变 比如
personal favorite being live
我们最爱的 Live Photo
photos but there's lots of
还有很多
content out there, short-form
别的形式如
video and so one.
短视频等等
Bandwidth continues to be at a
带宽依旧处于
premium.
非常重要的地位
And certain applications and use
在一些特定的应用程序
cases like over-the-top video
和使用情景中
delivery and wireless networks
如 OTT 视频交付和无线网络
place a premium on the amount of
对带宽的要求
bandwidth.
非常高
And anything we can do to reduce
降低带宽要求
the bandwidth requirements
会显著地
really helps out those use
改善这些
cases.
使用情景
So we've been using H.264 and
我们已经使用 H.264 和 JPEG
JPEG for a while.
有一段时间了
There are limits to what these
这些编解码器
codecs can do in this evolving
在迅速演变的格局中
landscape with these new
面对着这些新的挑战
challenges.
能做的事情很有限
And that leads us to HEVC.
这推动了 HEVC 的诞生
We were looking for a
我们一直在寻找一个
next-generation codec that we
可以在照片 图像
could use both for movies and
和视频中通用的
for photos or images.
新一代编解码器
And we were looking for
我们也一直在寻找
something that was going to give
某种能带来
us significant benefits over
显著收益的
what exists today.
技术
So having evaluated our options,
经过评估后
we decided to select HEVC.
我们选择了 HEVC
HEVC stands for High Efficiency
HEVC 是 High Efficiency Video Coding（高效视频编码）
Video Coding.
的缩写
It is a state-of-the-art
这是一种使用最先进技术的
industry standard that was
行业标准
adopted and approved in 2013.
在 2013 年被批准和采用
It was ratified by ISO as MPEG-H
ISO（国际标准化组织）将它批准为 MPEG-H 的第二部分
part 2 and by ITU as H.265.
ITU（国际电信联盟）将它批准为 H.265
We're going to be calling it and
我们将会用 HEVC
referring to it as HEVC.
来称呼和指代它
And Apple is adopting it as its
Apple 将把它作为
next-generation codec.
新一代的编解码器
So we'll spend a couple of
我们接下来将会用几分钟
minutes talking about what makes
来谈谈是什么让 HEVC
HEVC such a great codec.
成为了一个这么棒的编解码器
Now HEVC is similar to H.264 in
HEVC 和 H.264 很相似
that it is a codec that
它们都是
processes videos and frames in
分块处理
blocks.
视频和帧的
And it uses temporal and spatial
它使用了时间和空间
compression techniques to get
压缩技术来获得
the compression benefits.
压缩效益
Now H.264 has a notion of macro
H.264 的概念是基于宏块的
blocks, which are 16 x 16 size
也就是说在编解码器中
blocks that are used within the
进行处理时
codec for processing.
使用了大小为 16 x 16 的块
HEVC introduces notion of CTUs
HEVC 引入了 CTU
or coding tree units.
也就是编码树单元的概念
And these it start down at 4 x 4
这些单元的大小
and go all the way up to 64 x
可以从 4 x 4
64.
一直到到 64 x 64
And it's when you can use these
当你使用
larger sizes is when you realize
更大的单元时
the greater compression benefit.
你就会获得更好的压缩效益
And this is especially true when
当你处理
you're dealing with high
高分辨率视频和图像时
resolution videos and images.
尤其如此
You can really take advantage of
你真的可以
this.
充分利用这个性质
Similarly, H.264 had 4 x 4 and 8
H.264 使用了 4 x 4 和
x 8 DCT or discrete cosine
8 x 8 DCT  也就是离散余弦变换
transform, whereas HEVC not only
但 HEVC 不仅使用了
uses a discrete cosine
离散余弦变换
transform, it also uses a DST,
还使用了 DST
distribute sine transform.
也就是离散正弦变换
And similarly, with the coding
同样 由于编码块
block sizes for the transform
会针对变换块调整大小
blocks, it also goes up to 32 x
大小也会提高到
32.
32 x 32
To get better spatial
为了获得更好的
compression, HEVC introduces
空间压缩效果  HEVC 引入了
additional directional modes.
额外的定向模式
While H.264 had up to nine, HEVC
H.264 有最多 9 个
has up to 35.
相比之下 HEVC 提高到了 35 个
A key part of being able to do a
实现高度压缩
high degree of compression
的关键在于
involves motion estimation or
运动估计
motion compensation.
或运动补偿
And this is where you try to
这就是你要找的
find -- you basically have a
你想要根据前面的图像
block in your current image that
来预测当先的图像
you're trying to predict from a
在这之中
previous image.
有一个块
And what you can do is say, you
你知道你能通过它
know what?
做些什么吗
This block is that same block
这个块与上个图像的块
from the past but moved over by
是一样的 只是移动了
a certain number of pixels.
特定数量的像素
Sometimes you don't always land
有时你并不能
in a pixel's boundary.
刚好匹配到像素的边界
For example, you know, something
比如 一些内容
could have moved five pixels
可以移动 5 个像素
over but it could have moved
但是也可以移动
five-and-a-half pixels over or
5.5 个像素或者
five-and-a-quarter pixels over.
5.25 个像素
When you need to do motion
当你需要在半个像素
estimation at that half pixel or
或者四分之一个像素的边界
quarter pixel boundary, you need
进行运动估计时
to be able to generate those
你需要能够
pixels with accuracy and
精确地生成这些像素
precision because those don't
因为它们
exist.
不存在
You just have to pixels at the
因为只有边界上
boundaries.
才有像素
And so as you can see, HEVC has
所以 如你所见  HEVC 拥有
advanced filtering which can be
更好的滤波能力
used to generate those sub-pel
这可以用来
and quarter-pel pixels with much
更精确地生成
more accuracy and precision.
亚像素和四分之一像素
And that leads to better motion
这带来了更好的
estimation compensation and,
运动估计和运动补偿
hence, better compression.
从而带来更好的压缩效果
Finally, if you're familiar with
最后 如果你熟悉
block-based codecs, we talked
基于块的编解码器
about H.264 having macro blocks,
我们说过 H.264 使用宏块
sometimes you can actually see
有时你确实可以
in the coded video, artifacts
在编码视频中看到
around the edges of that block.
块边缘的缺陷
We call those blocking
我们称之为
artifacts.
块效应
H.264 introduced a loop filter
H.264 先前引入了一个环路滤波器
called the deblocking filter
叫做去块滤波器
that helps get rid of a lot of
它可以帮我们大幅减弱
those artifacts.
块效应
Now HEVC improves upon that
HEVC 是在这个滤波器的基础上改善的
filter, but it takes it a step
但它更进一步
further and introduces a second
引入了一个额外的步骤
sequential step where we run a
在这个步骤中
sample adaptive offset filter
我们会运行一个样本自适应偏移量滤波器
which gives us even better
它会给我们带来
results.
更好的处理结果
So now these are some of the
现在我们已经说了
highlights that give us a better
一些在 HEVC 中能给我们
compression in HEVC.
带来更好压缩效果的重点技术
And there is more.
其实还有更多
So having said that, how much
说了这么多
improvement are we talking
我们究竟能有
about?
多少提升呢
And this is why we're excited
这就是我们
about introducing this next
为什么这么兴奋地向你们介绍
generation codec at Apple.
这个 Apple 的下一代编解码器的原因
In the case of general video
在普遍的视频内容上
content, we're seeing an up to
我们能看到
40 percent compression
相较 H.264 最多 40% 的
improvement over H.264.
压缩效果提升
So you can generate the same
所以你可以生成
quality video as you were doing
与之前同等质量的视频
previously but reduced 40
但可以减少
percent less bandwidth.
40% 的带宽
Or you could keep the same
或者你可以保持
bandwidth and significantly
相同的带宽
improve the video quality.
并显著提升视频质量
And we've done quite a bit of
我们已经进行了很多的
subjective and objective testing
主观性和客观性测试
to fine-tune the video to
以微调视频
realize these benefits.
来实现这些收益
In some use cases, we're seeing
在一些使用情景中
an even greater benefit.
我们甚至看到了更高的收益
So we've really optimized our
我们优化了
end-to-end pipeline with the iOS
端对端流水线
Camera Capture.
改善了 iOS 的相机捕捉
And in this use case, we're
在这个使用情景中
seeing an up to 2x improvement
我们能看到相较 H.264
over H.264.
2 倍的提升
What this means is you're able
这意味着你现在
to now store twice as many
能够存储
movies as you could previously
相较之前 H.264
with H.264.
两倍多的电影
Let's talk a little bit about
我们现在来谈谈
the specifics of what we are
我们支持的
supporting.
细节
Like H.264, HEVC also has the
像 H.264 一样
notion of profiles.
HEVC 也有 Profile 的概念
And in HEVC, we're supporting
在 HEVC 中 我们支持
the Main profile, the Main Still
Main Profile
Picture profile, and finally the
Main Still Picture Profile
Main 10 profile.
以及 Main 10 Profile
So with the Main 10 profile, we
有了 Main 10 Profile
are now able to encode and
我们就可以
decode video with 10-bit
让视频的编码和解码
precision.
达到 10bit 精度
This means that you can
这意味着
represent more gray scales and
你可以在我们
more colors and increase the
端对端的流水线上
overall quality of the video
显示更多的
end-to-end across our pipeline.
灰度值和颜色
With HEVC, we are requiring the
在 HEVC 中 我们要求
hvc1 codec type for playback.
使用 hvc1 编解码类型用于播放
This means that the parameter
这意味着参数集合
sets have to be stored in the
需要存储在
decoder configuration record as
解码配置记录中
opposed to within the samples or
而不是存储在样本
the payload itself.
或是负载本身中
So make sure when you are
所以请确保
creating HEVC assets that they
你在创建 HEVC 素材时
are the hvc1 codec type to
使用 hvc1 编解码类型
enable playback within the Apple
以使其能够在 Apple
ecosystem.
生态系统中播放
Finally, we're lucky in that we
最后 非常幸运
can take advantage of the fact
HEVC 本身就适配
that HEVC naturally fits into
现有的文件格式
the existing file formats.
我们可以充分利用这一点
So it fits nicely within the
它能够很好地
QuickTime movie file format as
适配 QuickTime 电影文件格式
well as the ISO MPEG-4 file
以及 ISO MPEG-4
format.
文件格式
So we picked a technology that
所以 我们选择了一个
is well supported within the
无论是业界
industry and within Apple's
还是 Apple 生态系统
ecosystem.
都支持的技术
It has both hardware and
这里说的支持
software support.
包含硬件和软件两个方面
And later on in the
在稍后的介绍中
presentation, Gavin will go into
Gavin 会详细讲解
the details about where and how
HEVC 在哪些方面
that's supported.
以及通过什么方式受到支持
It works already with the file
HEVC 适用于
formats that we've talked about.
我们刚刚所说的文件格式
So it's supporting the QuickTime
也就是 QuickTime 电影文件格式
movie file format and within the
以及 ISO MPEG-4
MPEG-4 file format.
文件格式
And finally, it's an ideal codec
总而言之 它是一个
for both movies as well as still
无论对于电影还是静止图像
images, allowing us to use it in
都很理想的编解码器
place of H.264 and JPEG.
可以用来代替 H.264 和 JPEG
Now as I've mentioned, HEVC can
我已经提到过
use the existing movie file
HEVC 可以使用现有的电影
formats.
文件格式
That's not the case for when we
但对于照片和图像
want to use it for photos or
我们不能
images.
使用它
So we needed to find a different
所以我们需要寻找
file format that we could use
另一个文件格式
for images that would allow us
来让我们使用
to use HEVC as the codec and
HEVC 作为编解码器
that's where HEIF comes in.
这时候就需要 HEIF 了
So before we get into HEIF,
在详细了解 HEIF 之前
let's talk a little bit about
我们先讨论一下
the requirements that we wanted
要采用一个新的
satisfied when adopting a new
图像文件格式
file format for images.
须满足的要求
We wanted support for
我们想要支持
state-of-the-art compression
以 HEVC 作为首选项的
technology with HEVC being the
最先进的
primary consideration.
压缩技术
We wanted explicit support for
我们尤其想要支持
alpha and depth channels as
Alpha 和景深通道
primary asset types.
作为我们的首要素材类型
We needed support for animation
我们需要支持动态图像
with animated GIF or JIF and
如动态 GIF/JIF
Live Photo.
或 Live Photo
In addition to just still image
除了支持静态图像
support, we wanted support for
我们还想要
image sequences, to be able to
对图像序列的支持
compress and represent those in
来压缩并展现
a file format such as what
你在连拍中
happens when you're dealing with
所使用的
bursts of photos.
文件格式
And finally, with images getting
最后 随着
larger and larger in size, it
图像的尺寸
was important for us to be able
越来越大
to process these efficiently
能够高效地以
with low latency and a
低延迟和合理的过程
reasonable amount of
来处理这些图像
performance.
是非常重要的
So when you've got a massive
当你在获得一张
image, you want to be able to
巨大的图像时
download it and start to preview
你想要立即
it immediately.
下载并开始预览
And if you're interested in a
如果你只对一张大型图像中的
particular smaller region in a
某一小块特定的区域感兴趣时
much wider image, you want to be
你想要能够
able to just decode and process
只解码并处理
the relevant tiles.
相关的 Tile
And so we were looking for
所以我们在寻找
something that would allow us to
一种能够让我们
take advantage of this kind of a
利用这种流水线
pipeline.
的技术
So with these requirements in
为了满足这些要求
mind, we looked at a few options
我们考虑了几个选项
and we selected HEIF.
最终选择了 HEIF
HEIF stands for High Efficiency
HEIF 是
Image File Format.
High Efficiency Image File Format（高效图像文件格式）的缩写
And like HEVC, it is also an
与 HEVC 类似
industry standard that was
它也是一个行业标准
ratified by ISO in 2015.
在 2015 年被 ISO 批准
It's based on the familiar ISO
它是基于我们熟悉的
Base Media File Format.
ISO BMFF 的
It is extremely feature-rich.
它的功能非常强大
And it supports both individual
同时支持单个图像
images and sequences.
和图像序列
There are many use cases in
除此之外还有
addition to that, that are
很多这个文件格式
supported by this file format
支持的使用情景
which allows for future
允许我们在将来
extensibility.
进行拓展
It typically uses HEVC for
通常它使用
compression.
HEVC 进行压缩
It has the option where you can
你也可以选择
use other encoders.
使用其他的编码器
But at Apple, when we're
但在 Apple
generating HEIF assets, they
当我们生成 HEIF 素材的时候
will only be using the HEVC
仅会使用
encoder.
HEVC 编码器
So why do all this for images?
我们为什么为图像做这么多呢
We saw the benefits for movies
我们已经看到了新的文件格式
and videos.
为电影和视频带来的好处了
And for images, we're also
对于图像
seeing tremendous gains over
我们也能看到
JPEG.
相较 JPEG 而言的 巨大好处
So now using HEVC within HEIF,
使用 HEVC 与 HEIF
you're able to capture and store
你可以拍摄和存储
twice as many images as you were
的图像数量
able to previously with JPEG.
将是之前使用 JPEG 时的两倍
Let's talk a little bit about
我们来讨论一下
the different formats of HEIF
我们支持的
that we are supporting.
HEIF 的各种格式
So as I mentioned from an encode
我刚刚提到过
or asset creation perspective,
从编码或素材创建的角度来看
we're going to be using the HEVC
我们将会使用
encoder, which means we're going
HEVC 编码器
to be generating the .heic file
这意味着我们将会生成
extension or .heic.
.heic 文件扩展名
So that's what we're doing from
这是我们从素材创建的角度来看
asset generation perspective.
正在做的事情
So we'll be able to create and
我们将能够
play back those files.
创建和回放这些文件
In terms of playback, we're also
在回放方面
going to support decoding H.264
我们也将会支持解码
HEIF images and, more generally,
H.264 HEIF 图像以及
if there's another codec that's
其他我们系统支持的
supported within our system,
编解码器
we'll also be able to decode and
我们也能够解码
display those HEIF files.
和播放这些 HEIF 文件
There is a great video that one
我们的同事 Davide
of our colleagues [inaudible]
制作了一个很棒的视频
has done which will provide more
这个视频将会
information into the HEIF file
提供更多关于
format.
HEIF 文件格式的信息
So -- and I think he'll be
我认为他将会
posted sometime later today or
在今天晚些时候
tomorrow.
或者明天发布这个视频
So please be sure to check that
如果你想了解
out if you want more details
更多关于 HEIF 文件格式的信息
about the HEIF file format, the
各种 Atom 类型
different atom types, and how to
以及如何解析并处理文件
parse the file and process it.
请一定要看看这个视频
So now that we've talked about
我们已经讨论了这些新的技术
these new technologies, what
了解了它们是什么
they are and why we decided to
以及我们为什么决定在 Apple 采用它们
select them at Apple, we'd like
接下来我们会
to talk to you about how we are
向你们介绍一下
using them within the Apple
我们是如何在
ecosystem and then also provide
Apple 生态系统中使用它们的
some guidance on what you can do
并为你门提供一些指导
with these fantastic
让你们了解通过这些优秀的技术
technologies in your apps and
能在 App 中做些什么
use cases.
并介绍一些使用情景
And to talk you through that,
为了向你们介绍这些内容
I'd like to hand things over to
我想把时间
Gavin Thomson.
交给 Gavin Thomson
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks Athar.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Athar
So my name is Gavin Thomson.
我叫 Gavin Thomson
I'm one of the engineering
我是 Apple
managers for the camera and
相机和照片部门的
photo organization at Apple.
一名工程经理
OK. So with -- we just learned a
我们刚刚了解了
lot of the great benefits of
很多 HEIF 和 HEVC
HEIF and HEVC.
很棒的优点
But what are the ecosystem
但这些在生态系统中
implications?
有什么含义呢
So at Apple, we've been working
在过去的一年里
over the last year to adopt HEIF
我们在 Apple 一直
and HEVC into the Apple
致力于让 HEIF 和 HEVC
ecosystem.
适配 Apple 的生态系统
So today I would like to share,
我今天想和大家分享
talk about that adoption and
和讨论这个适配过程
share the changes that were made
以及为了帮助这个转变
to help with that transition.
我们做出的变化
Our goal is to make the
我们的目标是
introduction of these new
让这些
formats as transparent as
新格式的介绍
possible.
尽可能简洁明了
So there are three topics that I
我想要讨论
would like to talk about.
三个主题
First is creation: how and where
首先是创建
we can create HEIF image and
我们如何以及在什么情况下
HEVC movie content.
可以创建 HEIF 图像和 HEVC 电影内容
There is access: how and where
然后是访问
to access HEIF and HEVC movie
我们如何以及在什么情况下
content.
可以访问 HEIF 图像和 HEVC 电影内容
And finally transfer: so what
最后是转移
strategies do you need to
当你想在拍摄或支持的设备上
consider when you want to move
移动 HEIF 或 HEVC 内容时
HEIF or HEVC content off a
你需要考虑
capture or supported device?
什么策略
So first I'd like to start with
首先我想从
access.
访问开始说起
So we've discussed the
我们已经讨论了
extensibility of the HEIF format
针对图像的 HEIF 格式的
for images.
可拓展性
What are some of the
Apple 生成的
characteristics of the Apple
HEIF 图像
generated HEIF images?
有哪些特征呢
So as we heard, the file format
我们已经了解这种文件格式是一种
is an ISO Based Media format.
ISO 基础媒体文件格式
So those of you that have look
你们中如果有曾经
at the internals of the MP4 or a
查看过 MP4 或 QuickTime 电影文件内部的人
QuickTime movie file, be very
将会对 HEIF 的
familiar with the internal
内部架构非常熟悉
structure as they're based on
因为它们是基于
the same standard.
同一个标准的
So I want to reiterate here,
我想在这里重申
HEIF is a container format.
HEIF 是一种容器格式
Not too similar to the QuickTime
这与 QuickTime 电影文件格式
movie file format.
不是非常相似
It's got many more options and a
它相较于 JPEG 文件格式
lot more flexibility than a JPEG
也有更多的选择
file format.
并具有更高的灵活性
Now, our image payload is
目前 我们的图像负载
encoded using HEVC.
是用 HEVC 编码的
And as we've learned, that
我们已经了解
provides great compression
它提供了相较 JPEG
improvements over JPEG, up to
很棒的压缩效果提升
2X.
最高可达 2 倍
We also encode the image payload
同时 我们将图像负载
as 512 x 512 tiles.
分成 512 x 512 Tile 进行编码
And amongst other advantages,
与其他的优势相比
that provides great flexibility
这对于高分辨率内容的
for fast incremental loading of
增量加载
high resolution content.
将提供很棒的灵活性
We also have a 320 x 240
我们将使用
embedded thumbnail, which is
320 x 240 大小的嵌入式缩略图
four times the resolution but
相较我们目前使用的
only twice the size of our
160 x 120 大小的 JPEG 嵌入式缩略图
current 160 x 120 JPEG embedded
分辨率提升至 4 倍
thumbnail.
但大小仅为 2 倍
Why can we do this?
我们是怎么做到的呢
Because the thumbnail was also
这是由于
encoded using HEVC.
缩略图也是使用 HEVC 编码的
We still support an image, EXIF
我们依旧支持
metadata payload compatible with
EXIF 元数据负载
the payload that we capture in
它与我们在 JPEG 格式中
our JPEG format.
的负载相适配
So HEIF with the HEVC encoded
使用 HEVC 编码的
image will be identified in the
HEIF 图像将会
file system with a new extension
在文件系统中
.heic or .heic as we call it.
以 .heic 扩展名标识
So some will know this is a
一些人可能知道
breakaway from the DCF 8.3
这与 DCF 8.3 文件命名惯例
filenaming convention.
相违背
So if you have any assumptions
如果你在文件名解析器中
with your file name parsers, a
有任何的预设值
variant three character
比如扩展名为 3 个字符
extension, we now have the
你需要知道现在我们的
default still capture format
默认静态捕获格式
that has four characters.
含有 4 个字符
So where is HEIF decode
那么我们在哪些地方
supported?
支持 HEIF 解码呢
It's supported on all of our --
HEIF 在我们
it's available on all of our
所有支持的平台上可用
supported platforms that have
如安装了 macOS 10.3
macOS 10.3 or iOS 11 installed
或 iOS 11 的平台
but there's a variety of
但其实还有更多的
hardware and software support.
硬件软件支持
For iOS, we have hardware decode
对于 iOS
on the minimum config of the A9
我们在 A9 芯片及以上的配置上
chip.
提供硬件解码
An example, of which, is the
举个例子 也就是
iPhone 6S or the iPad Pro.
iPhone 6s 或 iPad Pro
On macOS, we have hardware
对于 macOS
decode support on the
我们在第六代 Intel Core
sixth-generation Intel Core,
也就是 Skylake 家族
which is the Skylake family of
以上的处理器
processors.
提供硬件支持
An example of that machine is
比如含有
the new MacBook with the
Multi-Touch Bar 的新 Macbook Pro
touchbar, but we have software
但是我们在
decode support on all of our
所有支持的 iOS 和 macOS 设备上
supported iOS and macOS devices.
都提供软件解码支持
So where do we have HEIF image
那么我们在哪些地方
support?
支持 HEIF 图像呢
ImageIO was Apple's lowest level
ImageIO 是 Apple 最低等级的
image framework.
图像框架
And it supports HEIF as a source
它支持 HEIF 作为解码源
for decode, incremental loading,
增量加载
metadata, and thumbnail
元数据
abstraction.
和缩略图提取
This is in line for their other
这与使用其他相同 API 的
supported image formats using
受支持的文件格式
exactly the same APIs.
是一致的
Core Image also supports HEIF as
Core Image
a source for real-time image
也支持 HEIF
manipulation.
作为实时图像处理源
And the PhotoKit APIs which
允许访问照片库素材
allow access to assets in the
的 PhotoKit API
photo library also supports
同样支持
direct access to HEIF, but I'll
直接读取 HEIF
talk about this framework in a
我会在
little more detail in the coming
接下来的幻灯片中
slides.
详细讨论这个框架
Many of Apple's many based
Apple 的许多
applications will also natively
基于媒体的应用程序也会
work with HEIF.
自然适配 HEIF
Notable amongst those is photos,
比如照片
preview, Quick Look but there
预览 快速预览
are also many others.
除此之外还有很多
OK. Let's move to our movie
好的 我们来看看我们的
format and talk a little bit
电影格式并讨论一下
about Apple captured HEVC
Apple 拍摄的
movies.
HEVC 电影
So the changes here aren't as
比起我们最新支持的图像格式
drastic as our newly supported
电影格式的变化
image format.
并没有那么大
We're still capturing using the
目前我们仍在使用
QuickTime file format but with
QuickTime 文件格式
HEVC coded video frames.
但其实视频帧是用 HEVC 编码的
As we've learned for Apple
我们已经了解到
captured video, we're getting
Apple 拍摄的视频
twice the compression that we're
将会获得相较 H.264
getting from H.264.
2 倍的压缩效果
And, once again, just to call
此外 我想重申
out again, we're using HEVC to
我们的图像和视频格式
encode both our images and our
都将会使用
video formats.
HEVC 进行编码
We also support both an 8- and a
我们也支持
10-bit encoding.
8bit 和 10bit 编码
So those of you that really care
对于你们之中非常在意
about image quality or deep
图像质量或者深色技术的人
color, we have a non-real-time,
我们在 macOS 上将会有
a 10-bit software encoder on
非实时的 10bit 软件编码器
macOS to satisfy your needs.
以满足你们的需求
You'll be happy to learn, with
你们将会很高兴知道
this new format, we have
在这个新的格式中
retained the three character
我们保留了 .mov
.mov extensions, so you won't
这个 3 字符的扩展名
have to update any of your
所以你们不需要为这个媒体格式
filename parsers for this media
更新任何
format.
文件名解析器
OK. So where do we have decode
好的 那么我们在哪里
support for HEVC movies?
为 HEVC 电影提供解码支持呢
So we have both 8- and 10-bit
我们有 8bit 和 10bit 解码
decode which is available on all
它们在我们所有支持的平台上可用
our supported platforms with,
如安装了 macOS 10.3
once again, macOS 10.13 and iOS
或 iOS 11 的平台
11, but there's a variety of
但其实还有更多的
hardware and software support.
硬件软件支持
So in iOS, we have both 8- and
对于 iOS
10-bit hardware decode on the
我们在 A9 芯片及以上的配置上
minimum config of the A9 chip.
提供 8bit 和 10bit 硬件解码
Once again, the iPhone 6S is an
这里依然可以用
example there.
iPhone 6s 作为例子
For macOS, we have 8-bit
对于 macOS
hardware decode in
我们在第六代 Intel Core
sixth-generation Intel Core
也就是 Skylake 家族
processor which is the Skylake
以上的处理器上
family of processors.
提供 8bit 硬件解码
And we have 10-bit hardware
我们在第七代 Intel Core
decode support on the
也就是 Kaby Lake
seventh-generation Intel Core
家族处理器上
processors or the Kaby Lake
提供 10bit
family of processors.
硬件解码支持
And we have both 8- and 10-bit
我们在所有
software decode across all of
受支持的 macOS 和 iOS 平台上
our supported macOS and iOS
提供 8bit 和 10bit
platforms.
软件解码
OK. So where do we support HEVC
好的 那我们都在哪里
movies?
支持 HEVC 电影呢
AVFoundation is the primal
AVFoundation 是管理电影的
framework to manage movies.
主要框架
And it supports play, create,
对于 HEVC 内容
and edit workflows for HEVC
它支持播放
content.
创建和编辑工作流
Once again, PhotoKit will vend
PhotoKit 会提供
original HEVC movies.
原始的 HEVC 电影
WebKit will also playback HEVC
WebKit 也可以播放
movies but only on devices that
HEVC 电影 但是只能在
have hardware acceleration and
拥有硬件加速的设备上
all macOS desktops.
和所有 macOS 台式电脑上
There's also support to
我们也支持以鼓励
encourage HLS streams using
使用 HEVC
HEVC.
作为 HLS 流媒体
This represents a great
这为提高
opportunity to improve network
网络吞吐量
throughput.
提供了一个很棒的机会
And, in fact, the session
此外 下一场会议
directly after this is going to
将会讨论
talk about this initiative in
更多关于此项创新
much more detail.
的细节
Also, we have many Apple
我们有很多
applications that will natively
Apple 应用程序
work with HEVC movies, you know,
自然适配 HEVC 电影
QuickTime player, Quick Look
比如 QuickTime 播放器 快速预览
photos but also FaceTime.
照片以及 FaceTime
This is a great example of HEVC
这是一个很棒的
usage to greatly improve network
提高网络吞吐量的
throughput.
HEVC 用例
So we have decode support for
总而言之  针对 HEVC
HEVC across all of our devices.
我们为我们所有的设备 提供了解码支持
What about playback?
那么播放呢？
This is where the distinction
可以解码和
between decodable and playable
可以播放之间有很重要的区别
is very important and
在 HEVC 中
particularly so with HEVC.
尤其如此
This is unfamiliar territory for
这是我们中很多人
many of us.
都不熟悉的一个地方
We don't have hardware
对于默认的拍摄格式
acceleration across all
我们并非在所有
supported devices for default
受支持设备上
capture format.
都有硬件加速
And this is a problem we haven't
这是一个我们长时间以来
had to deal with for a long time
都不需要处理的问题
as H.264 hardware decode is
因为 H.264 硬件解码
fairly ubiquitous at this point.
在目前非常普遍
So all of our movie formats are
我们所有的电影格式
decodable but on some software
都可以解码
systems, there will be formats
但是在一些软件系统上
that are much slower than
会有一些格式的解码
real-time and really only
速度远不能达到实时
supported for export or
且仅支持导出
transcode workflows.
或者转码工作流
So how do you make the
那么你如何判断
determination that a format is
在一个给定设备上
suitable for playback on a given
某个格式
device?
适合播放呢
So AVFoundation, through its
在 AVFoundation 的 API 中
API, supports the notion of
有一个概念叫做
"isPlayable."
isPlayable
And this indicates whether a
这指示着
device's video level supports
一个设备的视频等级
the movie for playback.
是否支持播放某个电影
If true, you should experience
如果它为真
smooth playback without
你将会体验到
incurring any significant power
流畅的视频播放
or [inaudible] cost for videos
而不会遇到任何
of extended durations.
显著的卡顿
For example, even though Apple
例如 尽管 Apple 拍摄的
captured 4K30 is decodable
4K30 在所有
across all of our supported
受支持的系统中
systems, it's unlikely to be
都可以解码
marked as playable on some of
但是在我们的
our older hardware like the
某些旧设备上却不能播放
iPhone 5S.
比如 iPhone 5s
So this is a call out to
这就需要我们的
developers.
开发人员了
It's really, really important,
在这个点上
at this junction, for you to be
时刻观察这些
observing these playable state
可播放状态
to ensure we provide the best
来保证最佳的用户体验
possible user experience.
十分重要
OK. For many developers, their
好的 对于很多开发人员来说
first interaction with original
他们与原始 HEIF
HEIF and HEVC content will be
和 HEVC 内容的
through one of the public photo
第一次互动是通过公开的
APIs.
照片 API
PhotoKit is the widely used
PhotoKit 是一个在 iOS 上
photos API on iOS.
广泛使用的照片 API
And during his conference,
在此次大会上
they'll be some announcements
会宣布一些关于
about its availability on macOS.
它在 macOS 上的可用性
So look to the what's new photo
请在明天参加
session tomorrow for more
关于照片新特性的会议
details on that, but it will
以了解更多细节
vend original HEIF and HEVC
它会支持原始 HEIF 和 HEVC
movie content.
电影内容
Also, the deprecated
过时的
AssetLibrary framework is still
AssetLibrary 框架
very popular in the development
在开发社区
community.
仍然非常流行
And it will also vend HEIF and
它也会支持 HEIF 和
HEVC content.
HEVC 内容
On macOS, there is also the
在 macOS 上
Media Library API.
我们还有 Media Library API
For this release, it will only
对于这个 API
be vending transcoded
它将只会支持
representations of HEIF and HEVC
转码的 HEIF 和 HEVC
as JPEG and H.264 have been an
因为 JPEG 和 H.264
equivalent resolution.
有相同的分辨率
Because of the popularity of
由于使用 PhotoKit 在
PhotoKit to access media on
Apple 平台上
Apple platforms, I wanted to
访问媒体十分流行
highlight some of the classes
我想要强调一些类
through which you can access
通过它们你可以
HEIF and HEVC content.
访问 HEIF 和 HEVC 内容
When requesting images, you use
当请求图像时
the PHImageManager.
你可以使用 PHImageManager
Through this class, you can
通过这个类
request original HEIF images.
你可以请求原始 HEIF 图像
Also, remember requesting video
此外 当请求视频
objects, you can also use the
对象的时候
PHImageManager to request HEVC
你也可以使用 PHImageManager
movies.
来请求原始的 HEVC 电影
For managing resources, we have
对于管理资源
the PHAssetResourceManager which
我们有 PHAssetResourceManager
allows you to manage all the
它可以让你管理
discrete resources in the photo
照片库中所有
library.
零散的资源
Amongst those could be HEIF and
这些资源可以是
HEVC content.
HEIF 和 HEVC 内容
And for edit workflows, we have
对于编辑工作流
the PHContentEditinginput.
我们有 PHContentEditingInput
And it will support HEIF image
它会支持 HEIF 图像
or HEVC movies as input to an
或 HEVC 电影作为
edit session.
编辑阶段的输入
So a point that I really want to
我想要着重强调
stress here is that if you're
如果你已经在
already using Apple frameworks
使用 Apple 框架
to manage media, the transition
来管理媒体
to HEIF or HEVC should be
那么转变到 HEIF 或 HEVC
transparent.
将会非常容易
On the other hand, if you
另一个方面 如果你有自己的
[inaudible] image or video
图像或视频堆栈
stack, you might need to revisit
你可能需要重新访问
that integration and possibly
那些集成内容并
consider adopting one of the
考虑采用一个合适的
appropriate Apple frameworks.
Apple 框架
Amongst those are ImageIO for
可选的框架有
images, AVFoundation for videos,
针对图像的 ImageIO
Core Image for video frame or
针对视频的 AVFoundation
image manipulation.
针对视频帧或者
We have UIKit for presentation.
图像处理的 Core Image
We have PhotoKit to access the
针对展示 我们有 UIKit
resources within the photo
针对访问
library.
在照片库中的资源 我们有 PhotoKit
So usage of HEIF and HEVC
通过这些框架
through these frameworks will be
来使用 HEIF 和 HEVC
transparent.
将会非常容易
I'm going to make a second call
我想向大家推荐
out to the session that we have
另一个将会在
Friday at 11:00 a.m. working
周五上午 11:00 举行的会议
with HEIF and HEVC.
叫做 使用 HEIF 和 HEVC
There are lots of great code
届时将会有很多关于
examples of using HEIF and HEVC
如何在这些框架下使用 HEIF 和 HEVC
with these frameworks.
的示例代码
I highly recommend it.
我强烈推荐
OK. That was access.
好的 以上就是关于访问的内容
Let's move on to creation.
我们继续来看创建
So where and how can we create
那么 我们如何创建
HEIF image and HEVC movie
HEIF 图像和
content?
HEVC 电影内容呢
So, as you can see, we currently
如你所见 我们目前
only have HEIF encode support
在 iOS 上仅在最低配置为
and hardware on iOS with minimum
A10 Fusion 芯片的硬件上
configuration being the A10
提供 HEIF 编码支持
Fusion chip, an example, of
这样的硬件包括
which, is the iPhone 7 and the
iPhone 7 和
iPhone 7 Plus.
iPhone 7 Plus
So the notable exception at this
这里要注意的是
point in time is HEIF encode
macOS 并不支持
support on macOS.
HEIF 编码
How do we create HEIF images?
我们如何创建 HEIF 图像呢
ImageIO supports HEIF as a
ImageIO 支持 HEIF
destination.
作为输出
So you could consider
你可以考虑
transcoding your JPEG resources
将你的 JPEG 资源
to HEIF for great storage or
转码为 HEIF 以获得更好的
network benefits.
存储能力或者网络收益
Also, the AVFoundation capture
此外 AVFoundation 捕获 API
APIs will support HEIF captured
将会支持直接
directly from the camera.
从相机拍摄 HEIF
As Athar said, so all the Apple
如 Athar 刚刚所说
camera modes will default to
所有 Apple 相机模式将会默认
HEIF with the bursts being the
生成 HEIF 格式
only exception.
连拍模式除外
So if you have installed the
如果你已经
seed builds on supported
在受支持的硬件上
hardware and you're taking
下载了开发者预览版
photos, you're capturing them in
那么当你在照相时
the HEIF format.
将会获取 HEIF 格式的照片
It's also worth reemphasizing
值得再次强调的是
that only the HEIC variation of
只有 HEIC 这个 HEIF 变体
HEIF is supported from code
在 Apple 框架的代码中
through Apple frameworks.
受到支持
So HEIF images with the .hvc
对于 .hvc 的 HEIF 编码图像
encoded image.
也是如此
Let's move to movie creation.
我们来看看电影创建
Here are at the table showing
这里是一个展示
where we have HEVC encode
我们在哪些地方
support.
支持 HEVC 编码的表格
So in iOS, we have 8-bit encode
在 iOS 中 我们在
support with minimum
最低配置为 A10 Fusion 芯片上
configuration of the A10 Fusion
提供了 8bit 编码支持
chip, the iPhone 7 for example.
比如 iPhone 7
On macOS, we have 8-bit hardware
在 macOS 中 我们在
encode on the sixth-generation
六代 Intel Core 处理器
Intel Core processor or the
或 Skylake 家族处理器上
Skylake family of processors.
提供了 8bit 硬件编码
And also on macOS in software we
另外 在 macOS 中
have a 10-bit encode support.
我们提供了 10bit 软件编码支持
How do we create HEVC movies?
我们如何创建 HEVC 电影呢
So AVFoundation is a framework
AVFoundation 是一个
for movie creation.
电影创建框架
And HEVC movies can be created
HEVC 电影可以在
through an AVFoundation export
AVFoundation 的导出阶段
session.
创建
So you could export H.264 to
你可以将 H.264 导出为
HEVC for great storage or
HEVC 以获得更好的存储能力
network optimizations.
或者网络优化
You can also capture HEIF movies
你也可以直接通过
directly through an AVFoundation
AVFoundation 的捕获阶段
capture session with a camera.
使用相机来直接拍摄 HEIF 电影
Also, all the current movie
所有当前的
camera modes will default to
相机录制模式都会默认生成
HEVC encoded movies.
HEVC 编码的电影
So, once again, if you've
所以 如果你已经
installed the seed builds and
安装了开发者预览版
you're taking movies, you're
在你拍摄电影时
capturing them as HEVC movies.
它们其实已经是 HEVC 电影了
That was creation.
以上是创建
Next we come to transfer.
接下来我们来讨论一下转移
So what questions should we be
在我们想要在创建设备
considering when we want to
或其他受支持设备上
transfer HEIF image of HEVC
转移 HEIF 图像
movies from a creation device or
或 HEVC 电影时
other supported devices?
我们需要考虑什么问题呢
When transferring HEIF or HEVC
在受支持设备上
off a supported device, you
转移 HEIF 或 HEVC 时
don't have the same ecosystem to
你没有与 JPEG 或 H.264 上
code support that JPEG or H.264
相同的生态系统
provides.
以提供代码支持
You might want to consider
你可能想要
transcoding.
考虑转码
There are a few approaches you
这里是一些你可能
might want to consider.
想要考虑的方法
The first and the simplest would
首先也是最简单的方法是
be to always transcode.
总是转码
Another option might be to
另一个选项可以是
support a capabilities exchange.
支持适用性互验
Let's start with looking at an
我们首先来看看
example for workflow where you
转码的
might always transcode.
工作流示例
In this example, you have your
在这个例子中 你有一个自己的
own social networking client
社交网络客户端
that allows users to add HEIF or
允许用户在时间线上
HEVC content to a timeline.
添加 HEIF 或 HEVC 内容
So with this architecture, there
由于这个结构
is really no opportunity to
想要评估所有
evaluate the capabilities of all
接收设备的适用性
the receiving devices and
是不可能的
possibly no server transcode
而且服务器可能
support.
没有能力进行转码
So the option here is to always
所以我们只能选择
transcode.
转码
So for this scenario, both
在这种情况下
supported and unsupported
受支持和不受支持的设备
devices would receive the
都会接收到
transcoded representation, for
转码后的文件
example a JPEG or H.264.
比如 JPEG 或 H.264
Another approach that we might
另一个我们可能会
want to consider is a
考虑的方法是
capabilities exchange.
适用性互验
Let's take a look at an example
我们来看看这种
of that workflow.
工作流的示例
So here you might have a
你可能有一个应用
application that is adopted,
采用了 Apple 的
Apple's Multipeer Connectivity
多点连接
APIs.
API
If you're exchanging media with
如果你正在与一个
a supported device, you don't
受支持设备进行媒体交换
want to incur the cost of
你不希望总是出现由
transcode and high network
发送转码后的
latency of always sending a
JPEG 或 H.264
transcoded JPEG or H.264.
导致的转码成本和高网络延迟
So you could introduce your
你可以在初始的
capabilities exchange in the
握手中引入
initial handshake.
可用性互验
The sending device would
发送设备将会
evaluate the capabilities of the
评估接收设备
receiving device and decide
的适用性
whether to transcode or not.
并决定是否转码
So the hope, over time, is that
我们希望 随着时间的推移
as the support for these formats
支持这些格式的情况越来越多
grows, the amount of times that
我们需要转码的次数
we need to transcode decreases.
越来越少
So this strategy is really
这个策略对于
suitable for both P2P and in
P2P 和客户端／服务器结构
client/server architectures.
都非常适用
So how is Apple handling many
那么 Apple 是如何处理
similar workflows?
这么多相似的工作流的呢
Here are a couple of examples.
这里是一些例子
So it's mail.
比如邮件
It's not really possible to
评估所有
evaluate the capabilities of all
接收客户端的适用性
the receiving clients.
不太现实
And we don't have server
我们也并没有支持转码的服务器
transcode support so before
所以在把 HEIF 或 HEVC
sending HEIF or HEVC as a mail
作为邮件附件发送时
attachment, we always transcode.
我们总是转码
Now for those developers that
对于那些有
have share extensions, we'll
分享扩展的开发人员
also transcode before handing
我们也将会在发送 HEIF 或 HEVC 之前
off a HEIF or HEVC.
进行转码
This simplifies that integration
不管怎样
for the time being anyway.
这简化了当前的集成
We've also adopted the
我们也针对
capabilities exchange for a
一定数量的工作流
number of workflows.
采用了适用性互验
Example of those, P2P and
比如 P2P
AirDrop.
和 AirDrop
So with these integrations, we
有了这些集成
always evaluate the capabilities
我们总会评估
of the receiver before deciding
接收端的适用性
whether to transcode or not.
并决定是否转码
So in summary, there are a few
最后
points with regards to HEIF and
有一些 HEIF 和
HEVC that I'd really like to
HEVC 的重点
highlight.
我想要强调一下
HEVC is Apple's next-generation
HEVC 是 Apple 的
codec, which we're going to use
下一代编解码器
for both encoding images and
我们将会在编码
videos and is providing up to
图像和视频中使用它
two times the compression
它将会为 Apple 拍摄的内容
improvement for Apple captured
提供多达两倍的
content.
压缩效果提升
We're adopting HEIF as our image
我们将会采用 HEIF
file format.
作为我们的图像文件格式
This image container provides us
这个图像容器将会
with a flexible format which we
为我们提供一个灵活的
can use well into the future.
在将来很好使用的格式
If you're using Apple frameworks
如果你正在 Apple 生态系统中
within the Apple ecosystem, the
使用 Apple 框架
transition to HEIF and HEVC
那么转变到 HEIF 和 HEVC
should be mostly transparent.
将会非常容易
But if you need to move that
但如果你需要
content outside of that
在我们的生态系统外
ecosystem, you should consider
移动内容
your transcoding options to
你需要考虑转码选项
provide the best backwards
来为我们的用户提供
compatibility for our users.
最佳的向后兼容性
And finally, we really want
最后 我们非常希望
developers to embrace HEIF and
开发人员们可以接纳
HEVC for creation and access
HEIF 和 HEVC
workflows as we believe this
作为创建和访问工作流
will provide great benefits to
因为我们相信
not only developers but all of
这将不仅为开发人员 更为我们的顾客
our customers.
提供很大的益处
So for more details on this
要想了解更多
particular session, you can go
关于这次会议的细节
to the following website, but we
你可以访问如下网站
also have a number of sessions
但我们仍有一系列别的会议
and labs.
和研究室
We can learn more about HEIF and
我们可以了解更多
HEVC.
关于 HEIF 和 HEVC 的内容
Just a few to highlight.
我想推荐几个会议
The session following this is
接下来的会议将会
advances in HTTP Live Streaming.
讨论在 HTTP 在线流媒体播放中的进步
We also have working with HEIF
在周五上午 11:00
and HEVC at 11:00 a.m. on
我们还有
Friday.
使用 HEIF 和 HEVC 的会议
We have a great video, which you
我们有一个很棒的视频
can learn more about the HEIF
你可以通过它来了解
image format.
更多关于 HEIF 图像格式的信息
Thanks for your time today.
谢谢你们今天参加会议
And we look forward to answering
我们希望在这周
your questions at the labs and
剩下的时间中
sessions for the rest of the
在研究室和会议中
week.
回答你们的问题
Thank you.
谢谢大家